<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://mohki.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mohki.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-03T12:41:06-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mohki.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mitch Yarchin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[switching ssh keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://mohki.com/blog/2014/01/31/switching-ssh-keys-for-github"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T14:12:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mohki.com/blog/2014/01/31/switching-ssh-keys-for-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re like me and have many different projects + github accounts, but always use the same machine, chances are you&rsquo;ll have trouble switching back and forth between ssh keys.</p>

<p>This process isn&rsquo;t succinctly described anywhere (sorry <a href="stackoverflow.com">StackOverflow</a>, but it&rsquo;s true), so let&rsquo;s walk through it.</p>

<p>Basically, if you&rsquo;re working on a personal project and you switch to something for work, you might find the terminal complaining when you attempt to push your changes to Github:</p>

<blockquote><p>Please make sure you have the correct access rights
and the repository exists.</p></blockquote>

<p>Here is the simple solution for Mac users:</p>

<ul>
<li>In your directory <code>USERNAME/.ssh/</code> there are a bunch of different files. The one named <code>id_rsa</code> is what will be used by default. If you have a different key for work (ie one that is not id_rsa), you will need to fix this.</li>
<li>Open up the file <code>config</code> in that directory. If it doesn&rsquo;t exist, create it.</li>
<li>Add the following to your config file (things in caps are what you need to provide.)</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>#work account
</span><span class='line'>Host github.com-WORK_GITHUB_ACCOUNT
</span><span class='line'>    HostName github.com
</span><span class='line'>    User git
</span><span class='line'>    IdentityFile ~/.ssh/WORK_KEY
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#private account
</span><span class='line'>Host github.com-PRIVATE_GITHUB_ACCOUNT
</span><span class='line'>    HostName github.com
</span><span class='line'>    User git
</span><span class='line'>    IdentityFile ~/.ssh/id_rsa</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Open up Terminal and navigate to the directory where you were trying to push new changes, but got the error.</li>
<li>Type <code>ssh-add -l</code></li>
<li>You will probably see id_rsa. Stupid default thing! Let&rsquo;s change it.</li>
<li>Type <code>ssh-add -D</code> to prevent it from using that key.</li>
<li>Type <code>ssh-add ~/.ssh/WORK_KEY</code> to make it use your work key.</li>
</ul>


<p>&hellip;Tada! So long as your WORK_KEY is indeed associated with your github account, this should let you switch between keys.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[new projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://mohki.com/blog/2013/11/10/new-projects"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:08:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mohki.com/blog/2013/11/10/new-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Haven&rsquo;t posted in a while. Here&rsquo;s a quick list of my latest side projects:</p>

<h3><a href="http://writz.mohki.com">writz.mohki.com</a> (coming soon)</h3>

<p><em>Writz is a collaborative story-telling app that let&rsquo;s users work with each other on a single story buy submitting &ldquo;components&rdquo; and combining them together. Similar to the campfire game &ldquo;pass the story&rdquo;, but with better tools for generating a truly interesting narrative.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://wix.mohki.com">wix.mohki.com</a></h3>

<p><em>Wix is a sleek, hassle-free wiki tool with nice ACL management for wikis and fast editing. You can make a wiki and add pages to it. Supports markdown.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://uselesshypothetical.mohki.com">uselesshypothetical.mohki.com</a></h3>

<p><em>This is my own minimalist take on the game &lsquo;would you rather&rsquo;. Let&rsquo;s you submit new useless hypotheticals, vote on existing hypotheticals, and more.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iTerm2 Left and Right shortcuts]]></title>
    <link href="http://mohki.com/blog/2013/09/19/iterm2-left-and-right-shortcuts"/>
    <updated>2013-09-19T11:22:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mohki.com/blog/2013/09/19/iterm2-left-and-right-shortcuts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven&rsquo;t grabbed <a href="http://http://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm2</a> yet, do that. It&rsquo;s a sweet replacement for the OS X Terminal app.</p>

<p>Anyway, you might notice that iTerm2 doesn&rsquo;t offer the standard OS X shortcuts for skipping to the next or previous word: Alt+Left arrow / Alt+Right arrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s how you set that up without modifying ~/.zshrc or anything like that:</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to Preferences</li>
<li>Click Profiles</li>
<li>Add a new shortcut key (&ldquo;+&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Under Keyboard shortcut, press option(alt) + left arrow key</li>
<li>Under Action, select &ldquo;Send Escape Sequence&rdquo;</li>
<li>Under Esc, input &ldquo;b&rdquo;</li>
<li>Add a new shortcut key (&ldquo;+&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Same steps as above, but input &ldquo;f&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;b&rdquo;</li>
</ol>


<p>Success!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[future video games]]></title>
    <link href="http://mohki.com/blog/2013/09/05/future-video-games"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T17:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mohki.com/blog/2013/09/05/future-video-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll probably use this blog for decent ramblings when I have them.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure this is a relief to you, my adoring fan, who fantasizes daily about my musings. I can see you now: on the edge of your seat, eagerly pondering what awesome thoughts lay cluttered behind my greasy eyeballs.</p>

<hr />

<p>Several weeks ago an apprentice of mine (ok, maybe it was just a colleague) was blabbering on about the future of video games and interactive multimedia.</p>

<blockquote><p>You see, Mitch, in the future we will all carry around these tiny little devices with enormous storage and processing power.
People will show up at each others houses where they have &ldquo;terminals,&rdquo; plug-in through a wireless connection and mess around with graphically-intense programs that we can&rsquo;t possibly comprehend yet.</p></blockquote>

<p>I disagree. I&rsquo;ve always thought that in the future, we&rsquo;ll have massive computers floating around in the cloud that will handle all the computational work of today&rsquo;s personal machines. Instead of owning a physical device with a hard drive &amp; processor, people will have nice-looking terminal screens that stream content and respond to input by sending it back out into the cloud. And maybe these terminal screens will be portable, or virtual, for easy and fast looking.</p>

<p>Internet connections will be so friggin&#8217; fast that we won&rsquo;t even have operating systems on our local machines, just a controller and some kind of display.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
