<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Thoughts on useless treasures]]></title>
  <link href="http://myarchin.github.io//blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://myarchin.github.io//blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-06T12:05:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://myarchin.github.io//blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mitch]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[future video games]]></title>
    <link href="http://myarchin.github.io//blog/blog/2013/09/05/future-video-games/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T17:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://myarchin.github.io//blog/blog/2013/09/05/future-video-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll probably use this blog for decent ramblings when I have them.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure this is a relief to you, my adoring fan, who fantasizes daily about my musings. I can see you now: on the edge of your seat, eagerly pondering what awesome thoughts lay cluttered behind my greasy eyeballs.</p>

<hr />

<p>Several weeks ago an apprentice of mine (ok, maybe it was just a colleague) was blabbering on about the future of video games and interactive multimedia.</p>

<blockquote><p>You see, Mitch, in the future we will all carry around these tiny little devices with enormous storage and processing power.
People will show up at each others houses where they have &ldquo;terminals,&rdquo; plug-in through a wireless connection and mess around with graphically-intense programs that we can&rsquo;t possibly comprehend yet.</p></blockquote>

<p>I disagree. I&rsquo;ve always thought that in the future, we&rsquo;ll have massive computers floating around in the cloud that will handle all the computational work of today&rsquo;s personal machines. Instead of owning a physical device with a hard drive &amp; processor, people will have nice-looking terminal screens that stream content and respond to input by sending it back out into the cloud. And maybe these terminal screens will be portable, or virtual, for easy and fast looking.</p>

<p>Internet connections will be so friggin&#8217; fast that we won&rsquo;t even have operating systems on our local machines, just a controller and some kind of display.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
